This is the complete knowledge graph of machine learning.
这就是完整的机器学习知识图谱。
It shows all the concepts and all the dependency relations between them.
它显示了所有的概念以及它们之间的所有依赖关系。
For instance, this node represents GPT, a concept that builds upon causal language
例如，这个节点代表 GPT，一个建立在因果语言基础上的概念
models, theory training, transformers, autoregressive models, neural networks, multi-head attention,
模型、理论训练、变压器、自回归模型、神经网络、多头注意力、
and many more, reaching back to the very foundations of mathematics.
还有更多，回到数学的基础。
Once we map out all the mathematical and algorithmic concepts in machine learning,
一旦我们绘制出机器学习中的所有数学和算法概念，
patterns start to emerge. We can see subfields and their connections, computer vision,
模式开始出现。我们可以看到子领域及其联系，计算机视觉，
natural language processing, probability theory, linear algebra, and many more.
自然语言处理、概率论、线性代数等等。
But here's what I find the most beautiful. From the directed graph structure,
但这是我认为最美丽的。由有向图结构可知，
we can infer a hierarchical order between nodes and truly see the foundations of machine learning.
我们可以推断节点之间的层次顺序，并真正了解机器学习的基础。
For instance, here's gradient descent, a concept that builds upon a few prerequisites,
例如，这是梯度下降，这是一个建立在一些先决条件之上的概念，
yet supports the entire machine learning world as we know it.
但支持我们所知的整个机器学习世界。
Let's start at the beginning. What is a knowledge graph?
让我们从头开始吧。什么是知识图谱？
According to Wikipedia, a knowledge graph is a knowledge base that uses a graph structure
根据维基百科，知识图谱是使用图结构的知识库
to represent and operate on data. They are often used to store interlink descriptions
表示数据并对其进行操作。它们通常用于存储互连描述
of entities, such as objects, events, situations, or abstract concepts,
实体，例如对象、事件、情况或抽象概念，
while also encoding relationships underlining these entities.
同时还对强调这些实体的关系进行编码。
In our case, the knowledge graph of machine learning is built from mathematical and
在我们的例子中，机器学习的知识图谱是根据数学和
algorithmic concepts, such as the derivative. As the derivative is defined by a limit of
算法概念，例如导数。由于导数是由极限定义的
real numbers, its closest prerequisites are the concepts real number, completeness,
实数，其最接近的先决条件是概念实数，完整性，
convergence, and limit in the knowledge graph. On the other hand, the concepts chain rule,
知识图谱中的收敛性和极限。另一方面，概念链式法则，
tangent plane, Taylor expansion, and many more build upon the notion of the derivative,
切平面、泰勒展开式等等都建立在导数的概念之上，
thus they are immediate descendants. By mapping out all the concepts of machine learning in this
因此他们是直系后代。通过在本文中列出机器学习的所有概念
way, we obtain a knowledge graph of 2,081 nodes and 5,149 edges. So, how did I build this?
这样，我们就得到了一个包含2081个节点和5149条边的知识图。那么，我是如何构建这个的呢？
The knowledge graph is constructed recursively. In the first step, I took 810 high-level
知识图谱是递归构建的。第一步，我拿了810高级
machine learning concepts, such as GPT, CatBoost, ResNet, and others. Then I asked
机器学习概念，例如 GPT、CatBoost、ResNet 等。然后我问
Claude to write a definition, such as a deep convolutional neural network that introduces
Claude 写一个定义，比如深度卷积神经网络，引入
skip connections, enabling the training of very deep networks by providing shortcut paths
跳过连接，通过提供快捷路径来训练非常深的网络
for gradient flow and making it easier to learn identity mappings. And extract the
用于梯度流并使学习恒等映射变得更容易。并提取
used components, such as convolutional neural networks, gradient, skip connections,
使用的组件，例如卷积神经网络、梯度、跳跃连接、
deep networks, identity mapping, and many more. These are added as new nodes to the graph,
深度网络、身份映射等等。这些作为新节点添加到图中，
then connected to the ResNet node. By repeating this process over and over,
然后连接到ResNet节点。通过一遍又一遍地重复这个过程，
we reach the fundamental mathematical concepts such as logical implication, set, and element,
我们了解基本的数学概念，例如逻辑蕴涵、集合和元素，
where we terminate the recursive search. After doing this for all 810 seed concepts,
我们终止递归搜索。对所有 810 个种子概念执行此操作后，
and performing a transitive reduction on the edges, we obtain the full knowledge graph.
对边进行传递约简，得到完整的知识图。
In our case, the graph is directed and ac-click. Let's find some patterns.
在我们的例子中，图形是定向的并单击。让我们找出一些模式。
First, by looking at the nodes that have no incoming edges, we find the five foundational
首先，通过查看没有传入边的节点，我们找到了五个基本的
concepts. Logical implication, logical conjunction, set, element, and equality.
概念。逻辑蕴涵、逻辑与、集合、元素和相等。
These are the level 0 nodes. Nodes whose longest path from level 0 nodes has length 1
这些是 0 级节点。从 0 级节点开始的最长路径长度为 1 的节点
are the level 1 nodes. These include subset, set intersection, natural numbers, ordered pair,
是1级节点。这些包括子集、集合交集、自然数、有序对、
and more. The process continues until all nodes are reached.
等等。该过程持续进行，直到到达所有节点。
What are the most important nodes in this graph? What are the pillars of machine learning?
该图中最重要的节点是什么？机器学习的支柱是什么？
For instance, gradient descent is widely accepted to be the go-to optimization algorithm.
例如，梯度下降被广泛认为是首选优化算法。
When mapping out its prerequisites and its dependence, we can see that while gradient descent
当绘制出它的先决条件和依赖关系时，我们可以看到，虽然梯度下降
builds upon only a couple of concepts, it is practically used by everything else above it.
仅建立在几个概念之上，但它实际上被其之上的所有其他概念所使用。
What's the scientific way to find such central nodes? One method is to compute each
找到这样的中心节点的科学方法是什么？一种方法是计算每个
node's betweenness centrality defined by the formula on the screen.
由屏幕上的公式定义的节点介数中心性。
Let's unpack this. The betweenness centrality formula of V computes the ratio of the total
让我们拆开这个包装。 V 的介数中心性公式计算总的比率
number of shortest paths between any two nodes S and T, and how many of those shortest paths
任意两个节点 S 和 T 之间的最短路径的数量，以及这些最短路径的数量
pass through V, then sums them up. In other words, betweenness centrality measures how
通过V，然后对它们求和。换句话说，介数中心性衡量的是
unavoidable a node is. The higher it is, the more likely you'll pass through V
节点是不可避免的。越高，越有可能通过 V
when going from one node to another. Among other metrics, I calculated the
当从一个节点转到另一个节点时。在其他指标中，我计算了
betweenness centrality for all nodes. To visualize this, let's make the node sizes
所有节点的介数中心性。为了形象化这一点，让我们设置节点大小
proportional to this metric. The top central nodes are neural network, real numbers,
与该指标成正比。最上面的中心节点是神经网络，实数，
completeness, convergence, backpropagation, limit, gradient descent, absolute value,
完整性、收敛性、反向传播、极限、梯度下降、绝对值、
distance, function, and matrix. What's more interesting is that these central nodes form
距离、函数和矩阵。更有趣的是，这些中心节点形成
a thin spine at the bottom of the graph. This is the true foundation of machine learning,
图表底部的细脊柱。这是机器学习的真正基础，
the concepts that the entire field builds upon. Of course, from a practical standpoint,
整个领域所建立的概念。当然，从实际的角度来看，
mastering machine learning is better from the top down. Pick a topic and trace back the
自上而下掌握机器学习效果更好。选择一个主题并追溯
knowledge graph. If you want to explore the knowledge graph of machine learning yourself,
知识图。如果你想亲自探索机器学习的知识图谱，
I made an interactive explorer for you to try. Check the link in the description.
我制作了一个交互式浏览器供您尝试。检查描述中的链接。
You can also find the source on github if you want to play around with the code.
如果您想尝试一下代码，也可以在 github 上找到源代码。
If you found this video valuable, consider subscribing and sharing it with your friends.
如果您发现该视频有价值，请考虑订阅并与您的朋友分享。
It really helps me creating more high quality content.
它确实帮助我创造了更多高质量的内容。
Thanks for watching, and see you soon. Cheers, TIVADAR!
感谢您的观看，很快再见。干杯，蒂瓦达！